

# MUHAMMAD EJAZ UL HUDA

- Dammam, Eastern Province
- +966564726724
- ejazhoda92@gmail.com

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An accomplished software developer specializing in Object-Oriented Design and Analysis with 6 years' experience in the full life cycle of the software design process using SharePoint 2010/2013/2016, C#, ASP. Net and SQL Server 2008/2012/2016 R2 and SSRS tools including requirement, definition, prototyping, proof of concept, design, interface implementation, testing and maintenance.

# **WORK HISTORY**

SharePoint Developer, 03/2020 - Current

DataServe, Dammam, Eastern Province

- Designed, developed and supported optimal performance and security of **Eastern Eamana SharePoint application.**
- Researched database management tools and advised SharePoint on appropriate application and implementation to achieve business requirements.
- Improved code integrity through TFS/SVN to achieve assigned responsibility with in a given timeframe.
- Developed multiple services and applications and processes by writing quality programming code using languages such as SharePoint 2013/2016, C#, ASP.net REST and SOAP API.

# Senior Software Developer, 03/2019 - 02/2020

Getz Pharma (Pakistan Largest Pharmaceutical Company), Karachi, Pakistan

- Supervised entire software development lifecycle from requirement gather cycle to final project delivery using Agile methodology
- Improved coding efficiency, securing code development through root cause analysis and innovative problem solving.
- Incorporated new technologies such as Nintex workflow to upgrade existing SharePoint workflow
- Exhibited software development best practice to achieve and surpass KPIs.
- Trained and managed a team of four of developers and discussed issues in order to provide resolution and utilize best practices.

**Software Developer**, 04/2017 - 02/2019

Getz Pharma, karachi, Pakistan

Developed Custom SharePoint forms for Getz Pharma head office employees

• Leaves Application

- Advance Application
- Overtime Application
- Sample Plan Application
- Vehicle Maintenance Application
- Travel request Application
- QA portal Application (Documents Library)
- Legal Portal Application (Documents Library)
- HR Portal Application
- Developed web Application for (Getz Pharma) field force where they can manage their Doctor call reporting, DR List and Monthly Tour Plan using Tools (ASP.NET,Orcale,javascript,Jquery)
- Developed REST API for Getz Pharma mobile application

# **Software Developer**, 04/2017 - 02/2018

# Almeezan Investment Management Ltd, karachi, Pakistan

- Developed SOAP Web Services for (1 Link) Customer Investment through ATM Channel.
- Enhancement and Modification in Web Application "Online Member Service Application" using Tools (ASP.NET, SQL Server 2008).
- Enhancement and Modification in Desktop Application (Real time) "Service Monitor" using Tools (VB.NET, SQL Server 2008).
- Developed Tax saving calculator for voluntary pension scheme and mutual funds.
- Developed Application "FMS Integration" data integration between CDC and ALMeezan.
- Developed Application "NCCPL Integration" data integration between NCCPL and ALMeezan.
- Develop all types of reports in crystal reports and Microsoft reporting service (.rdl).

#### **SKILLS**

#### **SharePoint**

- SharePoint 2010/2013/2016 Onpremises
- Nintex Workflows

# **Server Side Languages**

- C#,
- Asp.net webforms,
- MVC
- VB.net

#### **Client side Languages**

- HTML
- Bootstrap
- CSS

- AJAX
- JavaScript
- JQuery

#### Database

- SQL
- My SQL
- ORACLE

# **Reporting Tools**

- SSRS
- Bi reports
- Crystal Reports

# **EDUCATION**

#### Coursera

Introduction of Software Product Management: Certification

# CertiProf

Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate: Certification

Karachi Unversity , Karachi, Pakistan, 2014 Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

**DJ Sindh Government Science College**, Karachi, Pakistan, 2010 **Intermediate (Pre-Engineering)** 

**Programmer School**, Karachi, Pakistan, 2008 **Matriculation**